Guide to the Vice President for Development and University Relations records, 1820-2003 RG0005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Vice President for Development and University Relations records
1820-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of the Vice President for Development and Alumni Relations
RG0005
13.5 Linear Feet
Collection includes pamphlets, biographical sketches, correspondence, news releases, memorandums, photographs, videotape, and publications.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from Vice President for Development and University Relations.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Vice President for Development and University Relations of The George Washington University reports to the President. The name changed to Vice President for Development and Alumni Affairs in 1992 and again to Vice President for Advancement in 2002. Under the Vice President are the Associate Vice President for Advancement, Central University, the Associate Vice President for School Programs, and Associate Vice President for the Medical Center. These offices raise money for University operations and oversee fund raising campaigns and endowments to the University.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Scope and Contents
Materials in this collection include pamphlets, biographical sketches, correspondence, news releases, memorandums, photographs, videotape, and publications. They range in date from 1820 to 2003, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Vice President for Development and University Relations. Note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
Collection Organization
Organized into eight series: Departmental files; Alumni achievement awards; Honorary alumni; Photographs; Long range planing workbooks; Campus renderings; "GW giving"; and Fundraising and development.
Endowments; Fund raising; Photographs; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University
- Departmental files, circa 1980 - 1986; RG0005 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is a collection of fundraising materials, pamphlets, and a video campaign for The George Washington University.
  - "Campaign for GW" Solicitor's Guide, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    3 copies
  - "Campaign for GW" Special Gifts Phase, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Naming Gift Opportunities, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Campaign for GW", circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Campaign for GW" The Annual Fund, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    2 copies
  - VHS "Campaign for GW", circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    VHS tape
  - Beta "Campaign for GW" A presentation of GW, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Betamax
  - Beta "Campaign for GW", circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Betamax tape
  - Beta "Campaign for GW", circa 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Acceptance of Gilbert Stuart portrait of Burgess Allison, 1982-1983; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Alumni achievement awards, 1820-1982; RG0005 Series 2; 4.25 Linear Feet (Box 1, Box 2, Box 8, Box 7, Box 6, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  This series is a collection of biographical information on distinguished alumni and alumni achievement award winners. They range in date from 1820 to 1982.
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1820-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1830-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1840-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1850-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1860-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1870-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Distinguinshed Alumni, 1890-1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bozeman, Albert Snead, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Buxton, Bronson C., undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cocke, Charles Lewis, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coffin, George Y., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cook, Richard B., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dobson, Harvie A., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Harper, Cornelius, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pearcy, Rev. George, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Vanderveer, Albert, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Abbot, Charles Greeley, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Eva B., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Alumni Achievement Award winner
  - Adams, Joseph Q., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ahmed, Aftah, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Alpher, Ralph Asher, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Amram, David, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Myron S., undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Auerbach, Arnold, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Axelrod, Julius, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Barnes, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Barrett, Jesse W. Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Battin, James F., undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baughman, George F., undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Baum, Carter, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Belcher, Carl W., undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Belen, Frederick C., undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Benitz, Helena C., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bennet, James Van Benschaten, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Beveridge, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Black, Jim, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Block, Carl Morgan, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bouvier, Jacqueline, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bradford, Harold Keith, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brand, Vance, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brewster, Daniel, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brigham, Gertrude R., undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brin, Carlos N., undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Broome, Edwin Warfield, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Mary Agnes, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Vernon L., undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Broyhill, Joel T., undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Burnett, Arden L., undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Burns, Jacob, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Burton, Cameron W., undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Byrd, Robert C., undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Calver, George W., undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Calvert, Joan P., undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Camalier, Willard C., undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Carlson, Paul, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carr, William G., undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Coblentz, Catherine C., undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Coe, Conway Peyton, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Coe, Richard L., undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cohn, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Connelly, Mary M., undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Considine, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Cooper, Irving S., undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Coughlin, Mildred, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Crain, Darrell C., undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cunningham, Richard, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Dalwig, Paul G., undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Danzansky, Joseph B., undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Davis, Edwin L., undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Davison, Fredric E., undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dominick, John F., undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Draper, Elizabeth Kohl, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Driver, William J., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dulles, Allen Welsh, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dulles, John Foster, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dunn, Gordon E., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Elgin, Lawrence A., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ennes, Howard, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Evins, Joe L., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Federico, Pasquale J, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fishback, David, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fisher, Raymond G., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Fitzsimmons, James E, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Flemming, Arthur S., undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Folleard, Edward, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Ford, Elizabeth, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ford, John F., undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Fowler, Nellie F., undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Franzone, Royce F., undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Frome, Michael, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Fullbright, J. Willi, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Gamble, Ralph A., undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Gebhard, Louis A., undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Gibbs, Malcolm G., undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Gibson, Jonathan, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Girouard, Phillias Henry, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Glettler, Bernard U., undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Glover Jr., Charles, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Goddard, James L., undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Goodman, Julian, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Green, Elsie, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Groesbeck Jr., Bertram, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Haley, Andrew, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hallan, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harmon, Robert H., undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Harris, Patricia Roberts, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hastings, George S., undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hawkes, Dr. Anna Rose, 1938-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Haycock, Robert L., undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Haydon, Edith, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Helsley, William A., undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Herres, Robert T., undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Herrick, Lucille, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Hoffacker, Lewis, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Holmes, Chester, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Hopping, Louis M., undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Howard, Frances H., undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Howrey, Edward F., undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Hughes, Sarah T., undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Hurley, Patrick, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Jacobs, Leon, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - James, Eldon, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - James, Peter, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - James, William S., undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Jaworski, Leon, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Jex, Garnet W., undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Nelson, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Johnson's Family, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Johnston Jr., William Drum, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jones, Roger, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jones, Wesley J., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kause, Selma, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Keegan, Harry J., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Kendall, Mesmore, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Kenner, Albert Walton, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kent, Grace Helen, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kent, Tyler G., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Kerlan, Irvin, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kocvara, Stephen, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Ladd, Mark H., undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lawson Jr., William Josselyn, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Lepper, Mark H., undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Low, Robert A., undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Lowenstein, Allard K., undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Lucas, Martha Bob, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Ludlow, Clara Southmayd, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - MacPhail, Leland Standford, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Manion, Esther, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Marshall, Janet, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Martin, Rev. Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Mason, Jimilo, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Matthews, Burnita S., undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - May, Orville E., undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Mccandless, David A., undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - McCarthy, Walter T., undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - McCartney, Leah Brock, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - McCoy, Philbrick, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - McGuire, Marie, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - McPeak, William Wallace, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Mead, Sterling V., undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Mitcheel, James M., undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Murphy, Jospeh P., 1958-1966 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Nervo, Luis P., undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Noyes, Frank B., undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Nicholas, Louis B., undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Parsons, Irene, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Patton III, George S., January 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Prengel, Ruth S., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Proctor, James M., undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Rawalt, Maraguerite, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rhee, Syngman, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Richmond, Alfred Carroll, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Robinson, James A., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Romney, Lenore, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ronne, Finn (Mrs.), undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Santos, Jose, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Schoenfeld, Rudolph E., undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Schutt, Verryl G., undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Shapiro, Dave, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Shepard, Donald, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Simmons, James, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Addison T., undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Snelling, Walter O., undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Solal, Jean Louis, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sweeney, John L., undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Tenhouten, Elizabeth S., undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Thom, William Chester, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Thompson, Winfred G., undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Tirrell, Norton Quincy, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Tolson, Clyde A., undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tolson, Hillory A., undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Townsed, Marjorie Rhodes, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Truman, Margaret, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Warren, Hella, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wedel, Cynthia Clark, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Wells, Elva C., undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Wetmore, Alexander, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wheeler, Harold, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Wietzel, Frank H., undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Wilkinson, Ernest L., undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Willis, Benjamin C., undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wilson, John T., undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Wilson, William Lyne, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Wroe, Alderson, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Honorary alumni, 1851-1981; RG0005 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 3, Box 1)
  This series is a collection of biographical information and photographs of honorary and distinguished alumni. They range in date from 1827 to 1981.
- Photographs, 1895-1983; RG0005 Series 4; 3 Linear feet (Box 3, Box 2, Box 1)
  This series is a collection of photographs that range in date from 1895 to 1983. They include individuals, the 1967 commencement, the 1959 Glee Club, buildings, and more. Some of the individuals include Adelaide Hasse, Ainsworth Spofford, and Patricia Roberts Harris. Some of the buildings include the Law Center, Gelman Library, Thurston Hall, 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue, Academic Center Construction, and Funger Hall.
  - "Three Sisters" Fremont Davis, photographer, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
  - Woman Playing Violin, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
  - Modern Dance, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.3)
  - Woman Cutting Cake, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1.4)
  - Lloyd Elliot, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.5)
  - Photos of Negatives (1-27A and 0-34A). Joe Bailey, staff photographer from National Geographic, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.6)
  - Working with computers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1.7)
  - Henderson Presnell, 03/1938 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
    Copied by Mrs. Evans, of Handy studios from photograph loaned by Miss Wright, Assistant Librarian, Office of Education. Paid for by F.M. Hall.
  - Irene Gibson, circa 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
    Presented by brother-in-law (Detroit, Mich.) of Miss Gibson's
  - William Parker Cutter, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.3)
    Presented by Miss Barnett, Library. Dept. of Agriculture
  - Adelaide R. Hasse, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.4)
    Presented by Miss Hasse
  - W.D. Johnston, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.5)
    Reproduced from cut loaned to F.M.H. by Library Journal
  - H.H.B. Meyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.6)
    Presented by Mrs. Meyer
  - Ainsworth Rand Spofford, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.7)
    Copied by Mrs. Evans of Handy Studios from a photograph borrowed from Mr. Spofford's daughter. Paid for by F.M. Hall
  - Students Sitting in Class, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.8)
  - Patricia R. Harris, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2.9)
  - Parade, undated (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
  - Commencement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3.2)
    From left to right, Dr. Elmer Louis Kayser, University Historian; E.K. Morris, Chairman of the Board of Trustees; Senator Edward William Brooke of Massechusetts; and G.W. President Lloyd H. Elliot before a commencement in 1967. Senator Brooke received the honorary degree of Doctor of Laws.
  - Glee-Club, 12/1959 (Box 1, Folder 3.3)
    Singing Messiah with Singing Seargents and U.S. Air Force Orchestra
  - Law Center, undated (Box 2, Folder 1.1)
  - Gelman Library, undated (Box 2, Folder 1.2)
  - Thurston Hall, undated (Box 2, Folder 1.3)
  - Lincoln Memorial, undated (Box 2, Folder 1.4)
  - 2000 Penn. and Law Center 2000 Penn, 12/1980 (Box 2, Folder 1.5)
    Floor plans. Law Center elevations.
  - Negatives of 2000 Penn, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.1)
  - Aerial View of G.W. Campus and Downtown, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.2)
    Edison Bldg, Red Lion, Henry Bldg, Presidential Apts, G.W. Hospital, New Education Center, Metro Park, etc.
  - Academic Center, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.3)
    Ground work for the construction of the academic center and views of the completed academic center.
  - Funger Hall, undated (Box 2, Folder 2.4)
  - Media: G.W. Television, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - George Washington. George Washington silhouette. Statue of George Washington, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    ALL MISSING, 5/03 - SEE ACC#299 and ACC#133 FOR OTHERS
  - Collegiate Clothing: G.W. bookstore merchandise (sweatshirts, shirts, mugs, ties, etc.), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Organ from music department. Poster in exhibit (Photo by Harold Gray. Washington, D.C.) Other additional photos, 06/1935 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Only poster is dated. All other materials from this folder undated.
- Long range planning workbooks, 1970; RG0005 Series 5; 1 Linear feet
  This series is a two copies of a long range planing workbook for The George Washington University that was copyrighted in 1970. It includes factors influencing design, physical considerations, large area relationships, program, planning proposals, and implementation.
  - Long-Range Planning Workbooks, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    2 workbooks. Topics include: Factors Influencing Design, Physical Considerations, Large Area Relationships, Program, Planning proposals, Implementation
- Campus renderings, 1972-1985; RG0005 Series 6; 1 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series is a collection of renderings of campus buildings and scenes. They range in date from 1972 to 1985. The renderings include the Cloyd Heck Marvin Center, Dorothy Betts Marvin Theater, School of Medicine and Health Sciences, University Yard, Jacob Burns Law Library and Stockton Hall, University Yard, National Law Center, Alumni House, Academic Cluster [Center], Woodhull House, Eye Street Mall, Charles E. Smith Center for Physical Education and Athletics, University (Gelman) Library, and Lenthall Houses.
  - Cloyd Heck Marvin Center and Dorothy Betts Marvin Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - School of Medicine and Health Sciences, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University Yard, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    5 copies, with 2 signed by artist Peter Nelson with description of scene
  - Jacob Burns Law Library and Stockton Hall, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University Yard, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Colorized drawing
  - National Law Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architectural concept
  - Alumni House, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Academic Cluster, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    4 copies; now known as Academic Center
  - Woodhull House, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Eye Street Mall, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charles E. Smith Center for Physical Education and Athletics, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - University Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lenthall Houses, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "GW Giving", 1990-1993; RG0005 Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series is a collection of "GW Giving," a publication of the Development office. They range in date from 1990 to 1993.
  - GW Giving, 11/1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - GW Giving, 11/1990 -03/1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    2 copies of March issue, 1 of November issue
  - GW Giving, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Spring
  - GW Giving, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fundraising and development, 1887-2003; RG0005 Series 8; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains information concerning the development and fundraising campaigns of the University; endowments; financial gifts; wills; and other gifts. They include correspondence, memorandums, programs, annual fund reports, brochures, newsletters, and endowment reports. They range in date from 1887-2003.
  - Development Office, 1972-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Formerly vertical files
  - Development Office - Annual Fund Report, 1969-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Development Office - Annual Fund - Faculty Statements, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Development Office - Annual Fund, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Development Office - Annual Fund, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Development Office - Annual Fund Report - Honor Roll [1/2], 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Development Office - Annual Fund Report - Honor Roll [2/2], 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Development Office - Brochures, 1969-1990 -- --ca. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Development Office - Brochures - Tax Based Giving, circa 1962 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Development Office - Director Seymour Alpert, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Development Office - Luther Rice Society, 1969-1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Development Office - Organization of the Development Division and Annual Reports, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Endowments, 1920's, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Endowments, 1967-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Crises, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fund-Raising Activities, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising Activities - Anson Phelps Stokes, 02/15/1922-1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fundraising Activities - Campaign for George Washington - Campaign Brochure, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fundraising Activities - Campaign for George Washington - Campaign Chronicle - Vol. 1, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fundraising Activities - Campaign for George Washington - Campaign Chronicle - Vol. 2, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising Activities - Campaign for George Washington - Campaign Chronicle - Vol. 3, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fundraising Activities - Campaign for George Washington - Campaign Chronicle - Vol. 4, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Fundraising Activities - Centuries Campaign, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fund Raising Activities - Martha's Marathon, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Fund Raising - The George Washington Memorial Association, 1898-1904, 1897-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fund Raising - The George Washington University Movement, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Fund Raising - The George Washington Universtity Movement (Washington Site Fund Campaign) - Committees and Contributions, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fund Raising - The George Washington University Movement - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fund Raising - The George Washington University Movement - Statement of Facts and Objects, circa 1907 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gifts, 1962-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Gifts and Requests, 1887-1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Columbian College Departmental Publicity, 1986-2004; RG0005 Series 9; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is unprocessed, and material is in the order received.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains brochures, course catalogs, and newsletters from Columbian College of Arts and Sciences departments. Materials date from 1986 to 2004.
  - Columbian College "Arts and Sciences Update" event reservation form, undated; RG0005 Series 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology Brochure, undated; RG0005 Series 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fine Arts and Art History invitation, newsletter, prize information, 1993-2004; RG0005 Series 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)